Binder is the in the process communication mechanism used in Android.
Imagine that two people, Sam and John, are from different parts of the world and do not know a common
language.
They cannot understand the messages send across between them.
In this scenario, Sara, the professional translator, helps them communicate in the Android world.
Binder IPC does a very similar job by translating the messages across different processes in the system.
APC or interpersonal communication enables Android process to communicate and share services with each
other.
The APC of Android is called binding APC processes in Android how separate address spaces and a process
cannot directly access under that process memory.
It is called process isolation.
Process isolation is good for the security and stability of the OS.
However, suppose a process want to offer some useful services to other processes.
In that case, it needs to provide some mechanism that allows other processes to discover and interact
with those services.
That mechanism is referred to as APC or internal process communication binder, APC, Easter in the
process mechanism in Android.
And it is the cornerstone of Android's architecture.